<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Krystal Laryea</title><link>www.krystallaryea.com/projects/</link><atom:link href="www.krystallaryea.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Krystal Laryea</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/www.krystallaryea.com/media/logo_hu2c95a5947e4f04da9d6ebba2cd2300e9_58853_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Krystal Laryea</title><link>www.krystallaryea.com/projects/</link></image><item><title>Bridge: The pursuit of commitment across lines of difference</title><link>www.krystallaryea.com/projects/book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>www.krystallaryea.com/projects/book/</guid><description>&lt;p>My book dissertation explores the process of cultivating civic commitments across lines of difference within an institution that shapes American society: prestigious research universities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through two ethnographic cases – a progressive nonprofit for marginalized students and a Pentecostal campus ministry – I trace the experiences of students who see themselves as strangers on campus and navigate strangerhood through their participation in communal, identity-based groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Drawing on four years of fieldwork and 100 interviews with students, recent graduates, and organizational staff, I explore how students’ beliefs and moral commitments evolve, how they sustain rare identities through participation in communal groups, and the practical challenges they face trying to build inclusive organizations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How organizations relate to their environments</title><link>www.krystallaryea.com/projects/organizations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>www.krystallaryea.com/projects/organizations/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a member of the &lt;a href="https://pacscenter.stanford.edu/research/civic-life-of-cities-lab" target=_blank>Civic Life of Cities lab&lt;/a>, my colleagues and I are studying how nonprofits relate to their urban environments in cities across the world (San Francisco, Seattle, Shenzhen, Sydney, Singapore, and Vienna).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fellow team-member, &lt;a href="https://www.christofbrandtner.org/" target=_blank>Christof Brandtner&lt;/a> and I are writing a series of papers that examine the mechanisms by which organizations produce integration in their urban environments. Sociologists have found that the density of nonprofits influences urban outcomes, but there is a lack of clarity on how and why this happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We theorize a critical distinction between the organizational production of social integration (connecting people to one another) and systemic integration (connecting people to complex systems, such as the economy or politics). We then examine the organizational practices that enable the production of each.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our first &lt;a href="https://osf.io/preprints/socarxiv/ve85b/" target=_blank>paper&lt;/a>, which is under review, we identify two modal forms of expertise (street-level and suite-level expertise, embodied by staff and volunteers) that shape organizational capacity to produce social and systemic integration, respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our second paper, an invited submission to the RSO volume, &lt;em>Sociological Thinking in Contemporary Organizational Sholarship&lt;/em>, we theorize the internal processes that enable organizations pursue both forms of integration simultaneously: loose demographic coupling and communal anchoring. This paper advances work at the intersection of organizations and inequality by revealing how inequalities are justified in nonprofits, as women and minorities are relegated to the underpaid but morally valorized work of “community building.” A draft can be shared upon request.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Civic identities and participation</title><link>www.krystallaryea.com/projects/commitments/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>www.krystallaryea.com/projects/commitments/</guid><description>&lt;p>In an article under review (&lt;a href="www.krystallaryea.com/www.krystallaryea.com/uploads/laryea_reframing_2022.pdf" target="_blank">PDF available here&lt;/a>), I theorize how communal participation is sustained in the face of change, using the case of a religious community that shifted to a remote format during the coronavirus pandemic and highlighting the process of reframing in driving participation patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In an &lt;a href="https://meridian.allenpress.com/mobilization/article-abstract/27/2/125/483749/PREDICTING-THE-ONSET-EVOLUTION-AND-POSTGRADUATE?redirectedFrom=fulltext" target="_blank">article&lt;/a> published in &lt;em>Mobilization&lt;/em>, my colleagues and I draw on a longitudinal, mixed-methods study to show how predisposition and social movement involvement in college intersect to shape trajectories of activism and civic engagement over time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How culture shapes action</title><link>www.krystallaryea.com/projects/culture/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>www.krystallaryea.com/projects/culture/</guid><description>&lt;p>I examine how culture and meaning-making shape individual, social, and organizational outcomes in multiple independent and collaborative projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my paper, “Semiotic Shifts,” I advance existing debates in cultural sociology by theorizing how strategies of action evolve in the face of semiotic shifts, which occur when people enter institutional contexts and encounter new meanings for their beliefs. I theorize three modal strategies that people adopt in the face of semiotic shifts – distancing, bridging, and burrowing. I find that these strategies are linked to the cultural forms that students’ beliefs embodied prior to college (as common sense, tradition, and ideology). This paper is under review (&lt;a href="www.krystallaryea.com/www.krystallaryea.com/uploads/laryea_semiotic_2022.pdf" target="_blank">PDF available here&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a collaborative &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/00031224221076487&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1662414820016825&amp;usg=AOvVaw3eURDRSSCJplssFK6cST97" target=_blank>paper&lt;/a> recently published in &lt;em>American Sociological Review&lt;/em>, we use mixed methods to show how religious habitus shapes educational outcomes, especially for women. We argue that Jewish women grow up in religious cultural contexts that shape their self-concepts (and the centrality of higher education and career), which helps explain religious differences in vertical and horizontal stratification in educational attainment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With &lt;a href="https://positiveorgs.bus.umich.edu/people/elizabeth-trinh/" target=_blank>Elizabeth Trinh&lt;/a>, we are studying how nonprofit leaders strive to cultivate meaningful work environments and draw on personal sources of meaning to do so. Our first paper received a revise and resubmit from &lt;em>Administrative Science Quarterly&lt;/em>. A draft is available upon request.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, in an &lt;a href="www.krystallaryea.com/www.krystallaryea.com/uploads/laryea_ambiguous_2021.pdf" target="_blank">article&lt;/a> published in the &lt;em>Journal of Higher Education&lt;/em>, my colleagues and I theorize how people interpret and utilize ambiguous credentials, using the case of massively open online courses (a low-status credential offered by high-status universities). We reveal the risks and opportunities faced by learners seeking to leverage ambiguous credentials in the labor market.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>