<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>3 | Krystal Laryea</title><link>krystallaryea.github.io/publication-type/3/</link><atom:link href="krystallaryea.github.io/publication-type/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>3</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/krystallaryea.github.io/media/sharing.png</url><title>3</title><link>krystallaryea.github.io/publication-type/3/</link></image><item><title>Organizations as Agents of Social and Systemic Integration: Contradiction and Reconciliation Through Loose Demographic Coupling and Community Anchoring (under review)</title><link>krystallaryea.github.io/publication/laryea_agents_2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.github.io/publication/laryea_agents_2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reframing the Community: How Member Participation Shifts in the Face of Spatial Change (under review)</title><link>krystallaryea.github.io/publication/laryea_reframing_2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.github.io/publication/laryea_reframing_2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract:&lt;/strong> How is communal participation sustained in the face of change? I draw on the case of a collegiate religious fellowship that moved online during the COVID-19 pandemic to examine how individuals’ participation patterns evolve their community undergoes a collective shift.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Members’ participation trajectories were puzzling: core members moved on while periphery members moved in, often becoming core members. I explain this puzzle through the process of reframing, wherein individuals craft working lenses that answer the question “what does this community mean to me now?” This temporal focus reveals that those with the most positive frames (of the community as “beautiful”) before the shift struggled most to adapt, reframing the group as “not what it once was.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By contrast, periphery members with ambivalent frames prior to the shift came to reframe the group as beautiful, leading them to deepen their engagement. These findings have relevance for member participation in a variety of communal contexts as well as theorizing on framing more broadly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diversity as a Civil Religion</title><link>krystallaryea.github.io/home-unused/laryea_diversity_2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.github.io/home-unused/laryea_diversity_2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Street Smarts and Org Charts: Professional Expertise and The Production of Urban Integration (under review)</title><link>krystallaryea.github.io/publication/brandtner_street_2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.github.io/publication/brandtner_street_2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Up-playing Difference: The Micro-foundations of Inclusion in Group Life</title><link>krystallaryea.github.io/home-unused/laryea_up-playing_2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.github.io/home-unused/laryea_up-playing_2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Organizations and Their Significant Others: Collective Identity as a Dialogic Process</title><link>krystallaryea.github.io/home-unused/laryea_significant-others_2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.github.io/home-unused/laryea_significant-others_2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Semiotic Shifts: How Culture Shapes Religious Students’ Navigation of a Secular Institution (under review)</title><link>krystallaryea.github.io/publication/laryea_semiotic_2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.github.io/publication/laryea_semiotic_2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract:&lt;/strong> A central debate in cultural sociology is how culture shapes action. I advance scholarship on this question by theorizing how strategies of action evolve in the face of semiotic shifts, which occur when people enter institutional contexts and encounter new meanings for their preexisting beliefs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I draw on two years of ethnographic fieldwork and 49 interviews with conservative Protestant students attending an elite, secular university to empirically demonstrate how variation in forms of religious culture links to divergent strategies of action.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When religion takes the form of common sense, the dominant institutional culture brings about a semiotic shift and students’ distance from and reckon with their faith.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When religion takes the form of tradition, religious subculture brings about a semiotic shift and students bridge secular and religious meanings and spaces. Finally, when religion takes the form of ideology, students reject new semiotic axes and burrow into religious subcultures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bringing cultural and institutional theorizing into dialogue, this paper deepens our understanding of how culture matters as individuals learn to navigate new organizational contexts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leading The Way: Examining the Influence of Meaningful Work on Leadership (under review)</title><link>krystallaryea.github.io/publication/laryea_leading_2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.github.io/publication/laryea_leading_2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Meaning-Making at Work: Toward an Integrative Review and Framework</title><link>krystallaryea.github.io/home-unused/jiang_meaning-making_2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.github.io/home-unused/jiang_meaning-making_2022/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>