<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>organizations | Krystal Laryea</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/tag/organizations/</link><atom:link href="https://krystallaryea.github.io/tag/organizations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>organizations</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://krystallaryea.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>organizations</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/tag/organizations/</link></image><item><title>How organizations relate to their environments</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/organizations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/organizations/</guid><description>&lt;p>Christof Brandtner and I are writing a series of papers that examine the mechanisms by which organizations produce integration in their urban environments. Sociologists have found that the density of nonprofits influences urban outcomes, but there is a lack of clarity on how and why this happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We theorize a critical distinction between the organizational production of social integration (connecting people to one another) and systemic integration (connecting people to complex systems, such as the economy or politics). We then examine the organizational practices that enable the production of each.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our first paper, we identify two modal forms of expertise (street-level and suite-level expertise, embodied by staff and volunteers) that shape organizational capacity to produce social and systemic integration, respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our second paper, we theorize the internal processes that enable organizations pursue both forms of integration simultaneously: loose demographic coupling and communal anchoring. This paper advances work at the intersection of organizations and inequality by revealing how inequalities are justified in nonprofits, as women and minorities are relegated to the underpaid but morally valorized work of “community building.”&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>