<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>civil society | Krystal Laryea</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/tag/civil-society/</link><atom:link href="https://krystallaryea.github.io/tag/civil-society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>civil society</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://krystallaryea.github.io/media/icon_hu2c95a5947e4f04da9d6ebba2cd2300e9_58853_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>civil society</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/tag/civil-society/</link></image><item><title>Bridge: The pursuit of commitment across lines of difference</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/book/</guid><description>&lt;p>My book dissertation explores the process of cultivating civic commitments across lines of difference within an institution that shapes American society: prestigious research universities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through two ethnographic cases – a progressive nonprofit for marginalized students and a Pentecostal campus ministry – I trace the experiences of students who see themselves as strangers on campus and navigate strangerhood through their participation in communal, identity-based groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Drawing on four years of fieldwork and 100 interviews with students, recent graduates, and organizational staff, I explore how students’ beliefs and moral commitments evolve, how they sustain rare identities through participation in communal groups, and the practical challenges they face trying to build inclusive organizations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How organizations relate to their environments</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/organizations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/organizations/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a member of the &lt;a href="https://pacscenter.stanford.edu/research/civic-life-of-cities-lab" target=_blank>Civic Life of Cities lab&lt;/a>, my colleagues and I are studying how nonprofits relate to their urban environments in cities across the world (San Francisco, Seattle, Shenzhen, Sydney, Singapore, and Vienna).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fellow team-member, &lt;a href="https://www.christofbrandtner.org/" target=_blank>Christof Brandtner&lt;/a> and I are writing a series of papers that examine the mechanisms by which organizations produce integration in their urban environments. Sociologists have found that the density of nonprofits influences urban outcomes, but there is a lack of clarity on how and why this happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We theorize a critical distinction between the organizational production of social integration (connecting people to one another) and systemic integration (connecting people to complex systems, such as the economy or politics). We then examine the organizational practices that enable the production of each.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our first &lt;a href="https://osf.io/preprints/socarxiv/ve85b/" target=_blank>paper&lt;/a>, which is under review, we identify two modal forms of expertise (street-level and suite-level expertise, embodied by staff and volunteers) that shape organizational capacity to produce social and systemic integration, respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our second paper, an invited submission to the RSO volume, &lt;em>Sociological Thinking in Contemporary Organizational Sholarship&lt;/em>, we theorize the internal processes that enable organizations pursue both forms of integration simultaneously: loose demographic coupling and communal anchoring. This paper advances work at the intersection of organizations and inequality by revealing how inequalities are justified in nonprofits, as women and minorities are relegated to the underpaid but morally valorized work of “community building.” A draft can be shared upon request.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Civic identities and participation</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/commitments/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/commitments/</guid><description>&lt;p>In an article under review (&lt;a href="https://krystallaryea.github.io/uploads/laryea_reframing_2022.pdf" target="_blank">PDF available here&lt;/a>), I theorize how communal participation is sustained in the face of change, using the case of a religious community that shifted to a remote format during the coronavirus pandemic and highlighting the process of reframing in driving participation patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In an &lt;a href="https://meridian.allenpress.com/mobilization/article-abstract/27/2/125/483749/PREDICTING-THE-ONSET-EVOLUTION-AND-POSTGRADUATE?redirectedFrom=fulltext" target="_blank">article&lt;/a> published in &lt;em>Mobilization&lt;/em>, my colleagues and I draw on a longitudinal, mixed-methods study to show how predisposition and social movement involvement in college intersect to shape trajectories of activism and civic engagement over time.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>