<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts | Krystal Laryea</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/post/</link><atom:link href="https://krystallaryea.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Posts</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://krystallaryea.github.io/media/logo_hu2c95a5947e4f04da9d6ebba2cd2300e9_58853_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Posts</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/post/</link></image><item><title/><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/post/teaching/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krystallaryea.github.io/post/teaching/</guid><description>&lt;div style="border-radius:5px; border: 2px solid #BFC9CA; padding: 20px; background: #F4F6F6">I am committed to pursuing excellence in my teaching practice and fostering classroom environments that are inclusive, creative, rigorous, and supportive. I am equipped to teach courses related to sociological theory, organizational analysis, cultural sociology, sociology of education, sociology of religion, research design, and nonprofits and civil society at the undergraduate and graduate levels. I am also equipped to teach qualitative methods courses, including interviewing and ethnographic methods, for all levels.&lt;/div>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="past-teaching-experience">&lt;strong>Past teaching experience&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2021&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Teaching Assistant, Organizational Analysis, Stanford University (Masters / PhD)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2020&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Instructor, &lt;a href="https://ethicsinsociety.stanford.edu/outreach/hope-house-scholars-program" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hope House Scholars Program&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2019&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Teaching Assistant, Designing Research-Based Interventions to Solve Global Health Problems, Stanford University (Undergraduate)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2018-2021&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Graduate Fellow in Residence, Residential Education, Stanford University&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="invited-lectures">&lt;strong>Invited lectures&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2022&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Guest Lecturer on qualitative methods for Practical Approaches in Global Health Research, Stanford School of Medicine.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Discussant for &lt;em>How the Other Half Eats&lt;/em> by &lt;a href="http://priyafs.com/" target=_blank>Priya Fielding-Singh&lt;/a>. Center on Philanthropy and Civil Society Book Festival.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2021-2022&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Guest Lecturer on qualitative methods for Applied Research Methods in International and Comparative Education, Stanford Graduate School of Education.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>2020&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Guest Lecturer on &lt;a href="https://krystallaryea.github.io/uploads/laryea_ambiguous_2021.pdf" target=_blank>“Ambiguous Credentials”&lt;/a> for Sociology of Education, Stanford Graduate School of Education.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="quotes-from-former-students">&lt;strong>Quotes from former students&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Krystal&amp;rsquo;s detailed feedback, general encouragement, and insightful comments in class were very &lt;mark>helpful in my learning development&lt;/mark> throughout the quarter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;[Krystal is] very &lt;mark>engaging and considerate&lt;/mark> at the same time. I deeply appreciated her willingness to listen and help.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Krystal was thoughtful in marking memos and giving feedback; she would not only give line-by-line feedback, but would also give summarizing commentary that explained both high- and low-level feedback, which was incredibly helpful for the development of my ideas. She was very fair and clearly thought deeply about our memos; in class, &lt;mark>she would often make comments that tied together contributions from different students&amp;rsquo; memos, which speaks to the volume of effort&lt;/mark> that Krystal put into this class. Finally, Krystal is a deeply caring person, and repeatedly brought up (in 1-1 communications) aspects about my personal and intellectual development. I felt like Krystal was able to see me as more than a face on Zoom call but as a human being.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Krystal cares deeply about providing thorough and detailed feedback to students. She was &lt;mark>responsive, not afraid to challenge our thinking, and pushed me&lt;/mark> to go deeper into understanding the course content.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I really appreciated all the time that Krystal took into grading our memos. Each week &lt;mark>she would get them back to us the next day&lt;/mark> with tons of helpful feedback and comments.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>