<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>culture | Krystal Laryea</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/tag/culture/</link><atom:link href="https://krystallaryea.github.io/tag/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>culture</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://krystallaryea.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>culture</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/tag/culture/</link></image><item><title>How culture shapes action</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/culture/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/culture/</guid><description>&lt;p>I examine how culture and meaning-making shape individual, social, and organizational outcomes in multiple independent and collaborative projects. In my paper, “Semiotic Shifts,” I advance existing debates in cultural sociology by theorizing how strategies of action evolve in the face of semiotic shifts, which occur when people enter institutional contexts and encounter new meanings for their beliefs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I theorize three modal strategies that people adopt in the face of semiotic shifts – distancing, bridging, and burrowing. I find that these strategies are linked to the cultural forms that students’ beliefs embodied prior to college (as common sense, tradition, and ideology). This paper is under review; a preprint is available here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a collaborative paper recently published in American Sociological Review, we use mixed methods to show how religious habitus shapes educational outcomes, especially for women. We argue that Jewish women grow up in religious cultural contexts that shape their self-concepts (and the centrality of higher education and career), which helps explain religious differences in vertical and horizontal stratification in educational attainment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With Elizabeth Trinh, we are studying how nonprofit leaders strive to cultivate meaningful work environments and draw on personal sources of meaning to do so. Finally, in an article published in the Journal of Higher Education, my colleagues and I theorize how people interpret and utilize ambiguous credentials, using the case of massively open online courses (a low-status credential offered by high-status universities). We reveal the risks and opportunities faced by learners seeking to leverage ambiguous credentials in the labor market.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meaning-Making at Work: Toward an Integrative Review and Framework</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/publications/jiang_meaning-making_2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krystallaryea.github.io/publications/jiang_meaning-making_2022/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>