<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>culture | Krystal Laryea</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/tag/culture/</link><atom:link href="https://krystallaryea.github.io/tag/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>culture</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://krystallaryea.github.io/media/logo_hu2c95a5947e4f04da9d6ebba2cd2300e9_58853_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>culture</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/tag/culture/</link></image><item><title>The microfoundations of inclusion in civic institutions</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/book/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/book/</guid><description>&lt;p>My dissertation asks: &lt;em>how do people navigate institutional life together amid deep differences?&lt;/em> The demographic and ideological pluralism that marks modern societies is unprecedented. We are encountering diverse contexts that pose challenges to us as individuals, as well as any hope of forging deep community and cultivating shared institutions. Existing work highlights some of the mechanisms that drive and challenge exclusion and polarization – from homophily, social influence, and stereotyping to intergroup contact and social differentiation. But these theories do not account for the moral frameworks that guide action. I argue that we need to bring tools from cultural sociology to bear on the question of how to build community across lines of difference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To develop this approach, I focus on the case of how students with multiple minority identities navigate modern universities. I conducted a comparative ethnographic study of two groups: a diverse community of evangelical Christians at a secular, private university and a progressive nonprofit that serves underrepresented minorities at a prestigious, public university. Drawing on four years of fieldwork and 100 interviews, I identified and theorized three modal strategies of action that people deployed to navigate personal beliefs and identities pluralistic spaces: &lt;em>burrowing&lt;/em> (embedding in one group and foregoing others), &lt;em>distancing&lt;/em> (foregoing former groups, identities and/or beliefs), and &lt;em>bridging&lt;/em> (belonging to multiple, oppositional groups which requires reckoning with new beliefs while maintaining long-held belief anchors). An &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1AM_WW0rpOgwJ_ooxQHVBWRAM2_knQf3b" target="_blank">article&lt;/a> based on this analysis is under review.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the second half of my dissertation, I shift from focusing on how individuals navigate diverse contexts to focusing on how identity-based groups navigate internal diversity among their members. I consider how both groups that I studied acted as burrowing spaces for their core members (Chapter 4) but were transformed into bridging spaces through an interactional process that I call &lt;em>playing up difference&lt;/em>, where members bring non-shared identities and beliefs to the fore of group life (Chapter 5). An &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1SsW_KIC4CrsHTQPY_1kOElIXVqgROJtg/" target="_blank">independent article&lt;/a> based on Chapter 5 received an R&amp;amp;R from &lt;em>Sociological Theory&lt;/em> and won the ASA Theory section’s Best Graduate Student Paper Award.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In former projects, my work has examined how universities themselves act as agents of inclusion and exclusion in society. In a &lt;a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/00031224221076487" target="_blank">paper&lt;/a> published in &lt;em>American Sociological Review&lt;/em>, my (then-student) colleagues and I examine the mechanisms underlying the stratification of higher education by gender and religious subculture. We find that girls raised by Jewish parents develop self-concepts that facilitate their efforts to attend highly selective universities, underscoring the habitus that such organizations require. Additionally, in a first-author &lt;a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00221546.2020.1851571" target="_blank">paper&lt;/a> in the &lt;em>Journal of Higher Education&lt;/em>, we show how massively online open courses operate as ambiguous credentials, opening access to elite courses, but also risks as people strive to leverage such credentials in the labor market.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The mesofoundations of integration in modern cities</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/commitments/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krystallaryea.github.io/projects/commitments/</guid><description>&lt;p>My second line of research asks: &lt;em>when and how do organizations contribute to the production of meaning, community, and integration?&lt;/em> Sociologists have shown that the presence of organizations causally affects such outcomes as connectedness, social capital, crime, entrepreneurship, and crisis resilience. But extant studies leave unclear the &lt;em>processes&lt;/em> – both internal (among members) and external (in their environments) through which organizations produce personal, social, and systemic integration. I identify these processes through my work with the &lt;a href="https://pacscenter.stanford.edu/research/civic-life-of-cities-lab/" target="_blank">Civic Life of Cities Lab&lt;/a>, where we have collected data on over 600 nonprofits across six global cities. As part of this broader study, I led the collection of over 50 in-depth interviews with the leaders of Bay Area nonprofits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the production of meaning, I am spearheading a project on how organizational leaders strive to foster meaningful work environments for their staff. Drawing on in-depth longitudinal interviews that we conducted with 43 organizational leaders (before, during, and after the pandemic), we reveal the surprising fragility and fundamental relationality of meaningful work. This paper has received an R&amp;amp;R at &lt;em>Administrative Science Quarterly&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the production of integration, I am co-leading a series of papers that examine how organizational structures and practices shape the production of two types of integration: social integration, creating social ties among constituents, and systemic integration, connecting constituents to institutional resources. In our first &lt;a href="https://osf.io/preprints/socarxiv/ve85b/" target="_blank">paper&lt;/a>, we argue that organizations’ pursuit of social and systemic integration is linked to whether they prioritize suite-level (professional) expertise or street-level (experiential) expertise among their staff and volunteers. In a second, forthcoming paper, we examine what allows some organizations to pursue both forms of integration simultaneously.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, on the production of community, I have studied how community can be maintained in the face of change. In an &lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11133-023-09532-y" target="_blank">paper&lt;/a> published in &lt;em>Qualitative Sociology&lt;/em>, I use the case of how “Christian Fellowship” navigated the coronavirus pandemic to advance theorizing on how frames shape communal participation. I argue that reframing is triggered by temporal disconnect between past frames and present circumstances, present circumstances and imagined futures, or all three. My findings offer insights on how organizations striving to rebuild community post-pandemic might renew prior frames and fashion new ones.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meaning-Making at Work: Toward an Integrative Review and Framework</title><link>https://krystallaryea.github.io/home-unused/jiang_meaning-making_2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krystallaryea.github.io/home-unused/jiang_meaning-making_2022/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>