<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2 | Krystal Laryea</title><link>krystallaryea.com/publication-type/2/</link><atom:link href="krystallaryea.com/publication-type/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>2</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/krystallaryea.com/media/logo_hu2c95a5947e4f04da9d6ebba2cd2300e9_58853_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>2</title><link>krystallaryea.com/publication-type/2/</link></image><item><title>Predicting the Onset, Evolution and Postgraduate Impact of College Activism</title><link>krystallaryea.com/publication/mcadam_predicting_2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.com/publication/mcadam_predicting_2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract:&lt;/strong> The topics of differential recruitment to activism and its longer-term impacts have generated substantial empirical research. Yet, the lack of longitudinal studies of movement participation have limited our understanding of individual activism’s dynamics over time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here, we use six years of longitudinal survey data and two waves of interview data from a class of college students before, throughout, and after college to examine predictors of variation in college activism, the ebb and flow of activism over the course of college, and the effect of college activism on activism two years post-graduation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our findings dispute one consistent empirical claim in social movement studies and confirm another. Counter to the scholarly finding on the weak impact of predisposition on recruitment, we find that predisposition powerfully predicts variation in college activism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Consistent with the claim that significant early activism is linked with future activism, we find that students’ activism at the end of college significantly predicts their engagement in activism after graduation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>San Francisco Bay Area: A Left Coast Metropolis Grapples with Technocracy and Inequality</title><link>krystallaryea.com/publication/laryea_san_2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.com/publication/laryea_san_2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract:&lt;/strong> How do civic organizations in the San Francisco Bay Area straddle the paradox of challenging entrenched inequalities in an ostensibly progressive region that has been transformed by tech-driven wealth? Local nonprofits face the tension of maintaining access to elite resources while building connections to distribute those resources and navigate divides between the haves and have-nots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We draw on original data collected over the course of two decades on a representative sample of Bay Area nonprofit organizations. With rich information from both quantitative and qualitative data, we examine different aspects of nonprofits’ relationship to their constituents and environments, including their community embeddedness, cross-sector collaborations, and engagement in advocacy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We then turn to the internal operations of these organizations and survey the professional backgrounds of nonprofit leaders and the usage of practices that purportedly make nonprofits more professional, accountable, and digitally savvy. Our findings reveal a sector that is developing its own model of what community-directed management looks like, neither tethered strictly to a Left Coast ethos nor displaying uniform responses to strong institutional pressures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although the Bay Area sector pursues heterogeneous approaches to repairing social ruptures, there is a consistent theme of rebuilding and re-creating community. We argue that the region’s diversity in values, practices, and orientations stems from fighting deep fractures that resist simple solutions in a place marked by paradox.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Bat Mitzvah to the Bar: Religious Habitus, Self-Concept, and Women’s Educational Outcomes</title><link>krystallaryea.com/publication/horwitz_bat_2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.com/publication/horwitz_bat_2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract:&lt;/strong> This study considers the role of religious habitus and self-concept in educational stratification. We follow 3,238 adolescents for 13 years by linking the National Study of Youth and Religion to the National Student Clearinghouse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Survey data reveal that girls with a Jewish upbringing have two distinct postsecondary patterns compared to girls with a non-Jewish upbringing, even after controlling for social origins: (1) they are 23 percentage points more likely to graduate college, and (2) they graduate from much more selective colleges. We then analyze 107 interviews with 33 girls from comparable social origins interviewed repeatedly between adolescence and emerging adulthood. Girls raised by Jewish parents articulate a self-concept marked by ambitious career goals and an eagerness to have new experiences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For these girls, elite higher education and graduate school are central to attaining self-concept congruence. In contrast, girls raised by non-Jewish parents tend to prioritize motherhood and have humbler employment aims. For them, graduating from college, regardless of its prestige, is sufficient for self-concept congruence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We conclude that religious subculture is a key factor in educational stratification, and divergent paths to self-concept congruence can help explain why educational outcomes vary by religion in gendered ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
Received media coverage from: The Washington Post, Tulane News, Cornell Chronicle, NewsWise, Phys.org, Futurity, The Jewish Press, The Jerusalem Post, Reddit (Front Page), Jewish Telegraphic Agency, Religion News Service, and Rocket News.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ambiguous Credentials: How Learners Use and Make Sense of Massively Open Online Courses</title><link>krystallaryea.com/publication/laryea_ambiguous_2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.com/publication/laryea_ambiguous_2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract:&lt;/strong> Researchers have investigated the demography and styles of engagement of those who enroll in MOOCs but have lent little attention to how learners navigate MOOCs’ ambiguity as academic certifications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Analyzing semi-structured interviews with 60 people who devoted substantial time to at least one MOOC between 2014–2017, we find that people use MOOCs to build skills for application at work and home, build relationships, navigate life transitions, and enhance formal presentations of self, at the same time that they disagree on the meaning of MOOC completions as official academic accomplishments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our findings build theory on the multi-dimensional character of credential prestige that can inform educational social scientists and credential providers in an increasingly complicated postsecondary ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Purpose and Coping With Adversity: A Repeated Measures, Mixed-Methods Study With Young Adolescents</title><link>krystallaryea.com/publication/malin_purpose_2019/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>krystallaryea.com/publication/malin_purpose_2019/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Abstract:&lt;/strong> Purpose in life is associated with positive outcomes following adversity, but the mechanisms of this relationship are unclear. In this repeated measures, mixed-methods study, we examined the relationship of purpose to coping with adversity among young adolescents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A sample of 1357 adolescents completed a survey about purpose, negative life events, and positive reframing coping four times at six month intervals. A sub-sample of 91 survey respondents participated in an interview. Surveys were analyzed using fixed-effects and mixed-effects modeling to test the relationship between purpose and coping over time. Interviews were analyzed for purpose, adversity, and coping to understand this relationship as perceived by the participant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Survey results indicate that purpose and positive reframing coping are related and change together over time. Interview results suggest that purpose can be a response to negative experiences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are likely underlying factors or processes driving the relationship between purpose and positive reframing coping. Some of the potential underlying factors and processes are discussed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>